Hello, everyone. Welcome back to my SQL two groceries. Today, we are going to learn how to create the database in the MySQL.
The essential skill for managing your data is 50. First of all, here is simply explained for
what is the MySQL? Create database statement. So create database statement in MySQL is to create a new
database. Use the first step is set in a pure database environment. So first of all, you are starting
and create here the simple database. Now, okay. So now, when we start and in this field, the database
now, sample use for now, you can select for in the primary process step and here, first of all,
when I select create database, so define for create the database name. Use the simply compiled,
okay. So now, here are perfectly defined and create the database statement for
here, create the new database name. Suppose the company and operation. Now, just I can select and
then execute and you can see here the comment compiled successful because the operation is
successful for the MySQL. We turn a confirmation message for here. This message indicate the
database has been created, okay. So you can see here, create the confirmation message, okay.
So you can check for the database is created or not created. So now, just here, wait and in this
section, just reload and then go in for just press for the plastic, okay. And also just go for the
database into the database inside, just click and now just do it and you can see the completely
created for the company database, okay. So I hope you understand and now, next step here,
I can create the database with the character set and the collection, okay.
So now, just go for here and first of all, I can create for the database name,
suppose like these customers, okay. So it will create the customers and now,
just go again, okay. And then next step here, first, I can create the database name customer
and then I can set for the default character. So now, I can just type the default.
So now, just use the default for the character. So define simply the default character
with the set and use the default character, use first of all, understand for ETA
in the default character for reading the database section. And here, I can also just like
for here, the default. So here, you can use for the capital for it and it is called the
DFA, ULD, okay. So it is called the default.
And first of all, I can just type the UTF8 for MD code, okay. And use the underscore
and use here perfectly the unit code for the CI, okay. So this means,
so this means here in this default collection, this setting ensure profile handling
completely cleared for in this database, okay. So you can see here, I can create some
sample and use see here and not run in this statement, okay. And the next step just define
the another data coding and now here, create in the database for not exist. So you can use the
if not exist to prevent error if the database already exist. So first of all, there are
you move in this default character, session and start the create the database for using the,
I can just type for if and not or adjust, okay.
So the XI, SGA, okay. So I just hold here the cells now create for here the cells column, okay.
So simply just adjust this. So it is completely done in this example,
the first of all, create the database name, the cells only, and you can just try for the
create multiple columns. So now here, I can simply change use the cells this one and next step here,
I can create so just create for the data base for the cells to, okay. And also here,
it is for the multi personal, I will just try copy and then paste for here the next one,
change for this in the cell street format table, okay. So now just completely done and select
and execute and you can see here, just load and completely multiplication misses for completely
create this database, okay. So here, I'll just check verify this and just reload this stage and
this section and then bring the database inside and they can see here perfectly create for the
cells on cells to in the cell street database, okay. So here, completely done and perfectly
integrated the database in MySQL with some practical examples, okay. So I hope you perfectly
understand the session. So now just thank you for watching and happy recording, okay.